iia.ie 2010-06-23

# IIA Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy 

1\. Introduction

We at the Irish Internet Association (the "IIA") respect your right to privacy and comply with our obligations under the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003. The purpose of this website Privacy Statement is to outline how we deal with any personal data you provide to us while visiting this website. Naturally, if you are not happy with the content of this Privacy Statement you should not use this website.

By visiting the IIA website, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Statement. Any external links to other website are clearly identifiable as such, and we are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these other website.

2\. Types of Information Collected

We retain two types of information:

\- Personal Data

This is data that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you and may include your name, address, email address, user IP addresses in circumstances where they have not been deleted, clipped or anonymised, telephone number, and billing and credit card information. Such information is only collected from you if you voluntarily submit it to us. 

\- Non-Personal Data

Like most websites, we gather statistical and other analytical information collected on an aggregate basis of all visitors to our web site. This non-personal data comprises information that cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information regarding, for example, user IP addresses where they have been clipped or anonymised, browser types and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of our website.

3\. Purposes for which we hold your Information

\- Non-Personal Data

We use the non-personal data gathered from visitors to our website in an aggregate form to get a better understanding of where our visitors come from and to help us better design and organise our website. 

\- Cookies

This website uses "cookie" technology. A cookie is a little piece of text stored by the browser on your computer, at the request of our server. We may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your personal preferences so you do not have to re-enter them each time you connect to our website - our cookies are not available to other website.   
Cookies are required on the IIA website to allow users to access the Member's Extranet. No personal information is recorded, and the cookie is automatically deleted when you log out or close your browser. You are always free to decline our cookies, if your browser permits, or to ask your browser to indicate when a cookie is being sent. You can also delete cookie files from your computer at your discretion. Note that if you decline our cookies or ask for notification each time a cookie is being sent, this may affect your ease of use of this website. 

\- Personal Data

We will process any Personal Data you provide to us for the following purposes:  
a) to provide you with the goods or services you have ordered or requested;  
b) to contact you if required in connection with your order or to respond to any communications you might send to us;  
c) to send you the IIA Digital Digest Newsletter/Event Alerts and to communicate with you about association activities.

Please note all credit card or other payment information is transmitted using SSL encryption. All payment information details, including credit card numbers and bank details, are permanently deleted from our servers when the payment has been processed.

4\. Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

We may provide non-personal data to third parties, where such information is combined with similar information of other users of our website. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of unique users who visit our website, the demographic breakdown of our community users of our website, or the activities that visitors to our website engage in while on our website. The third parties to whom we may provide this information may include potential or actual advertisers, providers of advertising services (including website tracking services), commercial partners, sponsors, licensees, researchers and other similar parties.

We will not disclose your personal data to third parties unless you have consented to this disclosure or unless the third party is required to fulfill your order (in such circumstances, the third party is bound by similar data protection requirements). We will disclose your personal data if we believe in good faith that we are required to disclose it in order to comply with any applicable law, a summons, a search warrant, a court or regulatory order, or other statutory requirement.

5\. Sale of Business

We reserve the right to transfer information (including your personal data) to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of the IIA provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of this Privacy Statement and provided that the third party only uses your personal data for the purposes that you provided it to us. You will be notified in the event of any such transfer and you will be afforded an opportunity to opt-out.

6\. Security

Your personal data is held on secure servers hosted by TiBUS. The nature of the Internet is such that we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us via the Internet. No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. However, we will take all reasonable steps (including appropriate technical and organisational measures) to protect your personal data.

7\. Updating, Verifying and Deleting Personal Data

You also have a right to have your personal data corrected, if inaccurate, or, in certain circumstances, erased. Please forward any such requests by email to operations@iia.ie

8\. Right of Access to Your Personal Data

To find out what personal data we hold on you or to have your personal data updated, amended or removed from our database, please contact operations@iia.ie. Any such data subject requests may be subject to the prescribed fee.

9\. Changes to the Privacy Statement 

Any changes to this Privacy Statement will be posted on this website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any time we decide to use personal data in a manner significantly different from that stated in this website, Privacy Statement, or otherwise disclosed to you at the time it was collected, we will notify you by email, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in the new manner.

10\. Governing Law and Jurisdiction

This Privacy Statement is governed by the laws of Ireland and is subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the Irish courts.

11\. Questions or Comments

If you wish to contact us to discuss any matter in relation to this Privacy Statement or our processing of your personal data, please feel free to contact us by email at operations@iia.ie  

© 2010, 2011 Irish Internet Association, The Digital Hub, 10-13 Thomas Street, Dublin 8 | T: +353 (0)1 542 4154 | E: [info@iia.ie](mailto:info@iia.ie)  
The Irish Internet Association is Limited by Guarantee (having no share capital). Company Number 268 541.  
Registered Address: 70 Sir John Rogerson's Quay, Dublin 2, Ireland.
